

Nationality: British Visa: n/a

Linkedin: uk.linkedin.com/in/oliverbayesshelton/en Postal code: London, N20 9EG Email: me@bayes-shelton.co.uk www.bayes-shelton.co.uk **Mobile:** 07799880212 Website:

Software Developer / Technical Architect

A highly-motivated and driven software engineer with over seven years experience specialising in agile software development process, test driven development and application development for both web, mobile and wearable applications. With previous experience ranging from application developer, software engineer and cloud architect, I possess an adaptable skills-set which ensures I constantly meet critical deadlines in the demands of a fast paced environment.

Seeking an opportunity as a Software Developer or Technical Architect be it project based, freelance or contract where I can deliver immediate value and continue to build innovative software.

KEY SKILLS

- Cloud architecture
- RESTful API design
- Software development
- Linux systems administration
- Cyber security
- Continuous integration
- Configuration management
- Virtualisation
- **Business continuity**

TECHNOLOGY

Languages (PHP, C/C++, Java, Apex, Shell scripting, and others...)

github.com/obayesshelton

- DB (MySQL, NoSQL's)
- Methods/SDLC (Agile/SCRUM)
- Cloud infrastructure (AWS, EC2, S3, RDS, CloudFormation)
- Other (Jenkins, Nginx, Apache, Git, Github, TCP/IP, Puppet, Chef, Virtualisation)

AWARDS

- Medium Hall of Fame CVE-2014-0160
- Splitwise Responsible Disclosure CVE-2014-0160
- Eventbrite Hall of Fame CVE-2014-0160

REFERENCES: AVAILABLE ON REQUEST, RECOMMENDATIONS AVAILABLE VIA LINKEDIN

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

January 2015 - Present

ACADEMY OF FINANCIAL TRADING

World-wide leader in financial trading education.

Technical Architect

Technical Architect working part of a team formed of various different front and backend developers, reporting directly to the CTO. Tasked with building a whole new learning and financial trading platform working with the frontend team to allow Angular. JS to consume a RESTful API built in Laravel. The RESTful API data source was primarily Salesforce which was consumed via the Salesforce RESTful API. The team adopted a Test Driven Development (TDD) approach to all code written to allow the applications to be tested on every pull request and merge.



Selected Accomplishments:

- Successfully migrated the company from shared hosting to a multi instance AWS VPC consisting of various different tools such as EC2, CloudFormation, RDS, S3, CloudFlare, New relic and more...
- Introduced the company to a scrum methodology to help the CTO and directors understand project deadlines and deliverables
- Implemented a continuous integration solution to help with testing and release cycles
- Migrated the company from the Salesforce SOAP API to the Restful API
- Taught the team on using a git flow approach when developing their allocated work within the sprint

June 2014 - January 2015

LENDINVEST

World's largest peer-to-peer marketplace for real estate mortgages.

Senior Software Developer

Started in a small team without a CTO working together to maintain a legacy platform, After the arrival of the CTO a larger team of 8 consisting of front, backend developers and QA's was built to build a brand new investor / broker platform built in Symfony2 and Angular.JS. The team started to work within a Test Driven Development (TDD) approach, the team worked within a scrum methodology to deliver work every 2 weeks to the end user via continuous integration using Jenkins to allow the QA team to test all code on a regular basis to reduce bugs.

Selected Accomplishments:

- Introduced the company to PCI-DSS 3.0 to enable the platform to take payments
- Successfully migrated the company from Go Daddy shared hosting to a multi instance AWS VPC
- Part of the core team to redevelop the brand new investor / broker platform in Symfony2
- Implemented git into the development team to successfully source control the new platform
- Integrated an API to check every investor for anti money laundering to keep the platform compliant

October 2013 - May 2014

RANDOM STORM / COMPLY SEC

Random Storm - PCI ASV QSA, Penetration Testing, Vulnerability Management, Wireless and Managed Intrusion Detection services from the UKs leading security provider.

Comply Sec - A Governance, Risk and Compliance (GRC) platform, ComplySec provides an intuitive solution to protect your business and its information assets.

Software Developer

Brought in to develop a Governance, Risk and Compliance (GRC) platform, individually responsible for all code written, scoping out features, planning release cycles and fully virtualise the platform to be installed into clients virtual private clouds.

${\bf Selected\,Accomplish ments:}$

- Built a working prototype of the GRC platform and gave demos to some of Information Security leading experts and CIOs at InfoSec 2014
- Successfully single-handedly built a working prototype of the platform
- While working with the PHP framework Phalcon core contributions to the framework were made from developments with the framework



February 2013 - October 2013

Interactive Investor

An award-winning, online investment service that provides retail investors with financial information.

Software Developer

Part of the development team building a state of the art share trading platform for SharePrice, Interactive Investor and various white-label versions built in Zend. RESTful API's and XML data feeds were the main focus of the team. Data feeds were primarily used for historic price data, company fundamentals and RNS news which were an integral part of the platform.

Selected Accomplishments:

- Part of a two person team to successfully deliver the first client white-label platform
- Individually researched and conceptualised the use of TCP sockets to stream realtime prices from a thirdparty provider
- Individually worked with money wise which is a brand under ii to build a fund calculator

April 2011 - January 2013

SMARTASSESS / REALSMART

Smartassess is the the company behind Realsmart which is a virtual learning environment in more than 300 schools all over the world

Lead Developer

Brought in to work closely with the technical architect to maintain and introduce new features to the virtual learning environments written in Zend. Working with the developers and designers to maintain and update over 400 school websites using a Wordpress multi site network setup. Worked with the a freelance iOS contractor to develop a media uploader which integrated with a file manager written in Silex and stored in MongoDB and S3. All videos were encoded using ffmpeg in the same format to reduce delivery issues on multiple clients.

Selected Accomplishments:

- Managed a AWS virtual private cloud consiting of 15 instances and over 400 databases 1 for each school
- Introduced the company to a MVC framework (Symfony2 & Silex)
- Launched a file system application which to date has 2TB of data stored
- Built the companies first RESTful API which connected to MongoDB and S3

January 2010 - April 2011

SWITCH MEDIA / TOKYO DIGITAL

Switch Media - An award-winning digital, creative and technical agency specialising in web design, ecommerce, print design and hosting.

Tokyo Digital - Award winning digital agency based in the London UK and Liverpool UK.

PHP Developer

Started at Switch Media as the sole PHP developer to build and maintain all client portals, then brought into Tokyo Digital when Switch Media was sold to work on all PHP projects for various clients. Worked with Google to build the first book on the Google Chrome web store and successfully worked with the iOS team to deliver the first MOBO awards iOS app.

Selected Accomplishments:

- $\bullet \quad$ Created one of the worlds first Google Chrome Store apps
- Developed an iPhone app for the MOBO Awards which reached 20k downloads in one night.
- Created the companies first ever Facebook app and Google Chrome Store app



- Created and deployed the company's first e-commerce platform.
- Developed, deployed and optimised the companies first and only CMS.

EDUCATION

- Google Making Sense of Data (2014)
- University of Washington Building an Information Risk Management Toolkit (2014)
- University of Washington Information Security and Risk Management in Context (2014)
- Open University Certification in application development (2011)
- Open University Certification in server side development (2011)
- **Open University** Certification in client side development (2011)
- University of Maryland Cyber Security (2015)
- University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign Cloud Computing (2015)